<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dixit Patel</title>
    <link>https://dixitpatel.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dixit Patel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dixitpatel.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Fault-Tolerant Stack</title>
      <link>https://dixitpatel.github.io/2018/07/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dixitpatel.github.io/2018/07/06/</guid>
      <description>This, Software is eating the world , is a very interesting collection of (failry in-depth) articles exploring the interplay between modern technology and human life post tech hysteria of the early 2000&amp;rsquo;s. Here&amp;rsquo;s my favorite from the intro :
People change, then forget that they changed, and act as though they always behaved a certain way and could never change again. Because of this, unexpected changes in human behavior are often dismissed as regressive rather than as potentially intelligent adaptations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matter and Spacetime</title>
      <link>https://dixitpatel.github.io/2018/06/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dixitpatel.github.io/2018/06/03/</guid>
      <description>If we humans have at-least the perception of the difference between matter and spacetime and even though we are far from being able to explain the workings of it (Gravitons, Super String Theory), wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it also be worth putting efforts in understanding what allows us those perception in the first place ? And then interpolate to understand higher dimensions ? 
Here&amp;rsquo;s a thought of mine that will confuse you (and might make you believe that I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, but whatever) : Maybe we could develop an initial mathematical model based on the interactions between matter and spacetime as observed and use combination of HPC and Machine Learning to do simulations and inferences for alternatives and uncover other hidden knowledge ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Performance Computing and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://dixitpatel.github.io/2018/06/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dixitpatel.github.io/2018/06/01/</guid>
      <description>Equations are for eternity. 
Equations are elegant. Their concise nature that captures the underlying complexity of a system to a degree that satisfies &amp;lsquo;observed realities&amp;rsquo; are what scientists and mathematicians consider beautiful. A lot of discovery process for such equations, over the past, took approaches that combined mathematical modeling and computational sciences. Advances in High Performance Computing (HPC) greatly affected this process. In the HPC world, you start with a hypothesis, form a theory over the hypothesis, and additionally run experiments and simulations to build mathematical models that eventually might lead to discovery or newer ideas to explore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://dixitpatel.github.io/wisdom/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dixitpatel.github.io/wisdom/quotes/</guid>
      <description>I often come across inspirational content/quotes on youtube, blog posts, HackerNews, etc that I keep stockpiling into my Evernote. Below are tidbits from this diary of growing wisdom. Hope you like them!
 Bill Gates
 The best way to prepare as a programmer is to write programs, and to study great programs that other people have written. In my case, I went to the garbage cans at the Computer Science Center and I fished out listings of their operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>